71岁 癌症研究专家
71 years old, cancer research specialist
轻微震颤 两年前切除局限性黑色素瘤,有白内障
Minor tremors,localized melanoma,removed two years ago,cataracts.
而且他不能呼吸
And he can't breathe.
还不算脸部的伤痕
Also,disregard,the facial lacerations.
虽然很可怕 但与这次发病没关系
They're creepy,,but unfortunately irrelevant.
不想知道原因吗?
Don't you want to know why?
你用拐杖的原因
You have your cane.
不 是那些可怕伤痕的原因
No,why the lacerations,are creepy.
他晕倒的时候 在实验室里解剖大白鼠
He was about to dissect,one of his lab rats when he collapsed.
可以说 他整天弄老鼠
The little vermin seized,the day,so to speak,
结果把自己给搭上去了
and went medieval,on his ass.
怎么了? 我拉链开了?
What?,My fly open?
又开始疼了
So the pain's returned.
不疼 他没有意识了
There was no pain,,he was unconscious.
我想是因为他无法呼吸
I'm guessing because,he wasn't able to breathe.
我们是在说你
We're talking about you.
明显是 但明显我不是
Obviously.,I'm obviously not.
你们这些人怎么了?,我不用拐杖 你们觉得惊讶
What is it with you people?,I don't use the cane,you're shocked.
- 我用了...,- 我们只是关心你
I use the cane...,We're just concerned.
搞错对象了 我还能呼吸
About the wrong person.,I can breathe.
而那个Ezra Powell都快死了
Ezra Powell,on the other hand,,is gonna die.
那个Ezra Powell?
The Ezra Powell?
研究员? 写那本教材的?
Researcher? The guy who wrote,that textbook?
不是那本教材 就一本
Not that textbook,,the textbook.
等下 又一个你崇拜的医生?
Wait. There's actually,another doctor you admire?
我崇拜很多医生的
I admire lots,of doctors.
当然了 他们穿起膝袜来,比Ezra Powell好看多了
Of course,most of them look a lot better,in knee socks than Ezra Powell,
他们呼吸正常
but seeing,as they can all breathe...
基底被氧化
Oxygenation is,through the floor,
肺部充满了积液
and lungs are full,of fluid.
应该是心脏 可能是淀粉样变性病
Gotta be his heart.,Could be amyloidosis.
也许是肺,多年来在实验室吸入有毒化学物
Or his lungs,probably from years of inhaling toxic chemicals in his lab.
不是肺 胸片没问题
not the lungs,chest x-ray's clean.
心电图也好的 不是心脏
so's his ekg,it's not his heart.
我们太友善了
We're being too nice!
在医院外 他不能呼吸 医院里就行
Outside the hospital,he can't breathe,inside the hospital,he can.
因为我们帮了忙
Because we help.
足以干扰了检查结果
At least,enough to screw with our test results.
问题的症结不是在心脏就是在肺
Source of the problem's either in his heart or his lungs.
要做的就是停止帮助
So all we gotta do is stop helping.
施加压力 看哪个先崩溃
Put a little pressure on him,and see which gives out first.
71岁 心或肺一旦衰竭,很难复苏
At 71,we get his heart or lungs to give out,we might not get 'em to give in again.
所以才要在医院进行
That's why we're gonna do it in a hospital.
让他在倾斜的踏机上运动 作压力心电图
Put him on an incline treadmill,and do a stress ekg.
所谓仰慕不过如此
So much for the admiration.
开始吧
let's get you started.
把氧气调高
I'll turn your oxygen up.
我和William研究过这机器,最早的医疗方案
I-I worked with williams on the first protocol for this machine.
大家都还在用它
Everyone still uses it.
除了Williams
Except for williams.
他4年前去世了
He died four years ago.
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
享年84
He was 84.
他死于帆伞运动
He died parasailing.
他一直是个傻瓜
He was always an idiot.
你没事?
You okay?
哈
Oh,huh.
坚持住 医疗方案只几分钟
Hang in there,you knowthe protocol's only a few minutes.
心律平稳
his heart rate's flat.
不超过130 就什么也观察不到
We don't get it past 130,we're not gonna see anything.
要是摔倒 折了髋 一样观察不到
and if he falls and breaks a hip,we're not gonna see anything either.
除了增加医疗失当保险费
Except an increasein our malpractice insurance.
我料到House会再吃药片,可他又用拐杖了 回到之前
I figured house might go backto the pills,but if he's using his cane,he's right back to where he was before.
甚至更糟
Maybe even worse.
幸好 他能像个成人 坦然接受
Luckily,he'll handle itin a stoic,grown-up fashion.
他永远不会对我们表现出来
He'd never take itout on us.
我不行了
I can'T.
得停下
I've--I gotta stop.
再久一些
Just a little longer.
心律才90
heart rate's only 90.
把倾斜角加大
I'm gonna increasethe incline.
非得停下了
I gotta stop.
我要下来
I-I've gotta get off.
你做得很好 再快点怎样?
You're doing great,just a little faster,okay?
我可不要啦啦队长 要需要氧气
I--I don't needa cheerleader,I need oxygen.
停
Stop.
不起作用
This isn't working.
他的心律都没超90
His heart ratebarely got above 90.
他无法呼吸 肺里积液太多
He can't breathe,there'stoo much fluid in his lungs.
真的?
Really?
他肺里有积液?
He's got fluid in his lungs?
该怎么办?
Whatever are we gonna do?
哦 记得了
Oh,yeah,now I remember.
让他在踏机上 像轮轴上的老鼠一样跑
Put him on a treadmill,and run him like one of his ratson a wheel.
他跑不起来 几乎不能走
He can't run,he can hardly walk.
那是因为他还不够努力
That's 'cause he's not tryinghard enough.
如果加把劲 他的心率就会上升了
If he was,his heart ratewould go up.
肺里充满积液 运动起来会很疼
Exercising with a lungful of your own bodily fluidstends to hurt.
叫做压力测试 不是没有缘由的
They don't call ita stress test for nothing.
- 重新做测试,- 他快要溺弊了!
Do it again.,He's drowning!
把他从池子里拉出来 然后重新做
Then pull him out of the pool,and do it again.
我想这不是你的远期解决方案
I'm assuming this isn'tyour idea of a long-term solution.
需要排掉你肺内的积水 才可以做测试
We need to get rid of the fluidin your lungs so you'll be able to dothe test.
看看问题出在我的心脏还是肺
To see if it's my heartor my lungs.
就是这样
Exactly.
我这两样都花过钱了
My money's on both.
过去几年 我一直进进出出医院
I've been in and outof the hospital for the past year.
我又老又病
I'm old,i'm sick.
变得更老 病得更重
I'm getting older,and sicker.
不是非常有趣的鉴别诊断 但是--哦
Not a very interestingdifferential,but--oh.
进去了
I'm in.
你不需要一个400刀的手提包
You don't needa $400 handbag.
这样查你的喉咙有点难,如果你的牙床上下翻滚
It's kinda hardto check your throat when you're flappingyour gums around.
哦 不好意思
Oh,sorry.
但是为了秋季社交活动
But it's forthe fall formal.
他不会在乎 就算是为了总统就职典礼
He doesn't care if it's forthe presidential inauguration.
但是我穿Merissa的旧裙子 这不花钱
But I'm usingmarissa's old dress.It's free.
你知道还有什么是不花钱的?
Yeah,you knowwhat else is free?
你头上的屋顶 吃的东西 你的电话 电脑
Roof over your head,the food you eat,your phone,your computer.
你已经这样充血了多久?
How longhave you been congested?
一周 自从弗雷斯诺(加州中部城市)回来
A week,ever since we got backfrom fresno.
弗雷斯诺?
Fresno?
是在法国 对么?
That's in france,right?
看见帕特农神庙了么?
See the parthenon?
在加州
Uh,california.
我没有胃口 全身都痛 虚弱
I've got no appetite,I'm aching all over,I'm weak.
这样痛么?
Does that hurt?
哦 是的
Oh,yeah.
他说话总有这种不讨人喜欢的鼻音么？
Does his voice always havethat unattractive nasal tone?
完全正确
Totally.
你这么笑 我当成不
I'm gonna take that giggleas a no.
发烧 疼痛 虚弱 厌食
Fever,aches,weakness,loss of appetite.
最近有和静脉注射毒品的人有肛交么？
Been having any anal sexwith iv drug users lately?
当然没有 我结婚了
Of course not,I'm married.
你觉得她有没有可能-- 没有!
Do you thinkshe might've been-- no!
很可能是鼻病毒
It's probably a rhinovirus.
这是什么?
What's that?
感冒
Cold.
一天服用四次 离飞机远点
Take this four times a day,and stay off airplanes.
那是会飞的污水坑
They're flying cesspools.
你掉东西了
You dropped something.
想到什么 打电话给我
If there's anything elseyou can think of,please call.
怎么了?
Yes?
他太老 病重
He's too old and weak.
这个好 好太多了
Yeah,this is way,way better.
行得通
This'll work.
加把劲
Please,just try.
有20个词可以描述胸痛
There are 20 words to describechest pain.
烧灼痛 压榨感 刺痛 撕裂感
Burning,squeezing,stabbing,tearing.
每一种在诊断上都有用
Each onediagnostically useful.
因此 你们得感谢Powell医生写的课本
For that,you have to thank dr.Powell's textbook.
但没有词语能描述他此刻所感受到疼痛--
But there are no wordsto describe degrees of what he's feeling right now--
气喘
shortness of breath.
如果是他来研究这些课题 就会有的词
If he had worked on those issues,there would be.
如果没有答案他永远不会放弃
He never would've given upuntil he had an answer.
这不起作用
This isn't working.
House医生
Dr.House.
请别起来
Please don't get up.
你肯定很忙 我只是帮你加点速
I'm sure you're very busy,so I'm just gonna tryand speed things up a little.
是肾上腺素么? 这不在治疗方案内
Is that epi?That's not the protocol.
不是 你遵循治疗方案 都失败了
No,the protocol is whatyou tried to do and failed...each time.
心率超过100
up over 100.
现在我们有进展了
Now we're getting somewhere.
显示如何 foreman?
How's it look,foreman?
心电图没有变化
No ekg changes.
更猛一些吧
Then we push harder.
House 你会杀了他的
House,you're gonna kill him.
不 他是对的!
No,he's right!
让他这样做
Let him do it.
瞧见了? 这就是他为什么不需要穿中统袜
See?That's why he doesn'thave to wear knee socks.
他无法呼吸了
He can't breathe.
心率130
130.
这是魔力数字
That's our magic number.
这里没看头
Nothing here.
Foreman?
仍然没有阻塞迹象
Still no signof blockages.
表示说问题不在心脏 那么肯定是在肺部了
Which meansit's not the heart.So it must be the lungs.
瞧见了? 没有那么难 不是么?
See?Wasn't so hard,was it?
不!
No!
给我补上余下的肾上腺素
Just give me the restof the epinephrine.
测试结束 没问题 让你稳定下来
Test is over,it's okay,we're gonna stabilize you.
不!
No!
不 就让我死去
No,just let me die.
你不会死的
You're not gonna die.
不 我会的
Yes,i am.
会找到治疗方法的
We'll find a treatment.
我不要像这样活着
I don't wanna livelike this.
求你了
Please.
我求你了
Begging you.
杀了我
Kill me.
他不要再检查,他要我们帮他死去
he says no more tests,he wants to die and he wants us to help him do it
我要玩个小游戏 叫作,与米斯蒂·梅防守扣球 (排球名将)
And I want to playa little game I like to call block my spikewith misty may.
他经过深思熟虑 这不是冲动的决定.
He's thought this through,it's not an impulsive decision.
我的也不是
Neither is mine.
他心情抑郁
He's depressed.
治好以后 就会感觉好多了
He'll feel much betterafter we cure him.
他和我们都目睹了检查
He's seen l the testswe've seen.
即使搞清了引起肺损伤的原因,要扭转病情也太迟了
Even if we figure outwhat's causing the lung damage,it's too late to reverse it.
不知道问题所在 说不准的
You can't know that withoutknowing what's wrong.
他有权决定
It's his calL.
那么 我们怎么办?
So,what do we do?
把一个塑料袋罩在他头上来结果..?
Put a plastic bag over his headand get it over with?
不 给他满满一针的吗啡
No,we give him a syringefull of morphine.
我共事过的每个医生都曾做过
Every doctor I've everpracticed with has done it.
他们不想 也不喜欢这么做,但行医就是如此
They don't want to,they don't like to,but that's the way it is.
我没有过 我不会的
I haven't,I won'T.
我也做不了
I couldn't do it either.
你刚刚说过 要尊重他的决定
You just said we should respecthis decision.
尊重决定不意味着我们赞同它
Respect it doesn'tnecessarily mean we honor it.
是啊
Right.
意味着讨论一下
It just means we talk about it.
在某种意义上 "不伤害"意味着顺其自然
At some point,"do no harm"has to mean allowing nature to take its course,
而不是顽固的从中阻拦
not stubbornly standing in the way of it.
把金属针头插进静脉输液管,注入致命剂量的吗啡
Sticking a metal syringeinto a plastic iv line and pumping in a lethal doseof morphine
不叫作顺其自然
is not letting naturetake its course.
按照新泽西州的规矩 也不是
Not according to the stateof new jersey.
让他在积液中慢慢窒息 会更好些?
So it's better we allow himto slowly suffocate in his own plasma?
你到底站在谁那边 参议员?
Whose side are you on,senator?
开始是尊重他的意愿,一会入侵伊拉克 一会又撤军回国...
First respect his wishes,then invade iraq,then get the troops home...
下定决心
make up your mind.
当然有很多有趣的事情要考虑
Certainly a lot ofinteresting things to consider.
心电图排除了心脏的可能
Stress ekg rules outthe heart.
意味着有东西侵袭了他的肺部
Which means something'sgotta be attacking his lungs.
支原体肺炎或链球菌肺炎
Mycoplasma or strep pneumo.
问题是 做什么都已经太晚了
The problem is,it's too lateto do anything about it.
可以试试左氧氟沙星
We could try levofloxacin.
除非说服他值得试一试,否则想新的治疗方案毫无用处
Coming up with a new treatmentisn't gonna do us any good unless we convince himit's worth trying.
拜托 他又老 又病 又小个
Come on,he's old,sick,tiny.
可以对他为所欲为
We can do whateverwe want to him.
发生了什么?
What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
他肯定是掉下床了 把鼻套管勒在脖子上
He must've fallen out of bedand got the nasal cannula wrapped around his necksomehow.
Ezra 你在做什么?
Ezra,what are you doing?
我不要接在机器上活下去
I don't want to livehooked to machines.
太--太过虚弱不能自理屎尿
Too we--too weak to wipemy own ass.
你为什么要自理屎尿 如果有人看护
Why would you want to wipe your own ass,when you could havesomeone do it for you?
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
肯定还有其他的病人 你真的可以帮助
There must be other patientsyou could actually help.
不 所有的服务都是先到先得
No,all services renderedon a first come,first served basis.
我不会同意再做任何测试
I won't consentto any more tests.
如果有人要碰我 我会控诉被袭
And if anyone tries to so muchas touch me,I'll press chargesfor assault.
好吧 都听到了
Okay,well,you heardthe man.
他不人要管他
He wants everyoneto leave him alone.
你为什么不先走?
Why don't you go first?
出去!
Get out!
你来求医的
You came to me.
不是我来找你的
I didn't come to you.
我想时机到了 你有胆量去做的
I figured you'd have the gutsto do what had to be done if it came to that.
离这个还很远
We're nowhere near that.
该检查你肺部了
It's time to testyour lungs.
呼吸
BreathE.
你总会要呼气的
You're gonna have to exhalesometime.
停住!
Stop!
House 你弄疼他了
House,you're hurting him.
你弄疼我了
And you're hurting me.
好吧
Fine.
你不想帮我们 我们也帮不了你
You don't want to help us,we don't help you.
你的肺里慢慢充满积液
Your lungs slowly fillwith fluid.
你想喘过气来 但做不到
You gasp to catch every breath,but never can.
呼吸越来越费力
Every breath is petrifying.
缓慢 痛苦 充满折磨
It'll be slow,painful,torturous.
我们不能选择出生
We don't choose our birth.
也不能选择死亡
And we don't chooseour death.
如果可以如何?
What if you could?
做个交易怎么样?
How 'bout we make a deal?
你再多给我一天
You give me one more day.
到时如果没能找出你的问题,我帮你结束生命
If I don't find out exactlywhat's wrong with you by then,I'll help you die.
House.
House
24小时
24 hours.
拜托 又不会要你的命
C'mon,it's not gonnakill you.
老家伙 肺部 积液 开工
Old guy,lungs,fluid,go.
你不能帮助他自杀
You cannot help himkill himself.
当然可以 chase说一直这么做的
Of course I can,chase sayswe do it all the time.
Cuddy不会让你这么做的
Cuddy's not gonna let you.
够了!
Enough!
你不想要我结果他 好的
You don't want meto kill him,fine.
吓你一跳
Here's a big shock.
我也不想杀死他
I don't wantto kill him either.
我怎么能不杀死他?
How do I not kill him?
就你们这水平?
By you guys doingyour job.
有24小时来搞清楚 他出了什么问题
We have 24 hours to figure outwhat's wrong with him.
嘀嗒 嘀嗒!
Tick-tock,tick-tock!
我来培养细菌 若是肺炎
I'll draw cultures.,Pneumonia.
血液里应感染细菌
Should be bacteriain his blood.
24小时不够
That's gonna take longerthan 24 hours.
离心样本就够
Not if I spin downthe sample.
分离血沉棕黄层 对细菌作革兰氏染色
Separate off the buffy coat,then gram stain for bacteria.
好 做淀粉酶 D二聚体 C反应蛋白检测尿,和支气管痰液检查
Great,do an amylase,d-dimer,c-reactive peptide,get a urine,and doa bronchial sputum while you're at it.
你检查他家里和实验室,辐射和毒物源头
You, check his home and labfor radiation and toxins.
骨髓活检
And do a bone marrowbiopsy.
24小时内完成?
All of that in 24 hours?
不急 做不完就等,尸体解剖的时候做
Nah, whateveryou don't get done,,you can finishat the autopsy.
哇 你们看起来真糟
Wow,you guys looklike crap.
有什么结果?
What do you got?
手被染成紫色了
Purple dyeon my fingers.
骨髓活检有什么结果?
What'd the bone marrow biopsyshow?
没有结果
Don't have the results.
什么?
What?
你们整个晚上都在干什么?
What have youbeen doing all night?
豪饮狂欢罢了
Jell-o shots and wild sex,what else?
血液培养基中没有细菌
there's no bacteria in the blood cultures.
有些还在热处理, 但目前...
We still have some cooking,but so far...
没发现
nothing.
尿液也没有发现
Nothing in the urine.
实验室干净得可以做手术 确实也做手术
The lab was clean enoughto do surgery in because,well,they do.
老鼠身上也没发现病毒或跳蚤
There was no sign of viruses or fleas on any of the ratS.
是么?
Yeah?
谁?
Who?
让她打给诊所
Well,tell her to calla clinic.
让她留个口讯 我稍候联系她
Then tell herto leave a message,and I'll get back to her.
留个私人口讯
Then tell her to leavea personal message.
是谁?
Who's that?
Your prot間?
你要保护的人
这是什么?
What are these?
口述录音带 他什么都录音
Dictation tapes,he records everything.
为什么?
Why?
因为他是个勤奋的研究员?
Because he'sa diligent researcher?
或许他记忆衰退
Or he's losing his memory.
很多人录音笔记
Lot of people dictatetheir notes.
如果认为是这样 就一无所获
Yes,we could assume that,and we'd have nothing.
如果把这看作是疾病症状,同时影响了他的肺和脑
Or we could assume it's a symptom,in which case,whatever's in his lungs is also in his brain.
除非你查到更有突破性的
Unless you got somethingmore promising.
我去给他头作核磁共振成像
I'll go get an mriof his head.
继续检查 直到有发现
Keep testing untilyou find something.
我去办公室休息一会
I'm ing to my officeto rest for awhile.
我很长时间没上解剖学课了
It's been a long timesince I took an anatomy class,
但我肯定 你们的检查越来越远离肺了
but I'm pretty sure you'removing farther and farther away from my lungs.
转到其它地方察看
Running out of places to look,aren't you?
我们不会停止寻找
Doesn't meanwe're gonna stop looking.
在六个小时内不会
Mm,no,not for six more hours.
你希望我们失败?
You want us to fail?
不
No.
但你们会失败
But you will.
细胞核无异常 不是白血病
No abnormal nuclei means no leukemia.
他喝酒?
He a drinker?
根据病史 不喝酒
Not according to the history.
要么他喝酒 一个现成好理由,能解释这些非细胞形态
Which means,yes,he drinks,which gives us a nice,mundane explanationfor the acellularity.
也许他说的是真话
Or he's telling the trutH.
还剩下真菌感染没排除
Which means fungusis still on the table.
那你对人性的认识就被摧毁了
But your entire viewof human nature gets destroyed.
好坏参半
Six of one,half a dozenof the other.
坏消息来得快
Bad news fast.
好消息 则花多点时间
Good news,you cantake your time.
头没事 你错了 他的大脑能力没受损
Head's clean,you were wrong,his faculties are intact.
太糟了
Too bad.
要是他脑子坏了 就不用听他的了
If his brain was addled,we wouldn't have to listento anything he says.
给我10%的KOH
Hand me the 10% koh.
4点了 没查出病因
It's 4:00,we have nothingto tell him.
就不用跟他谈了
Then we have no reasonto talk to him.
还没有排除真菌
Still haven't ruled out fungus.
排除了 没有病菌 没有菌丝
Yep,we have,no bugs,no hyphae.
好 下一步
Okay,next procedure.
偷偷溜进去 把钟往回拨
We sneak in,turn back the clock.
整队人
Whole team.
肯定是坏消息
Must be bad news.
不 骨髓活检显示是多样骨髓瘤
Nope,bone marrow biopsyrevealed multiple myeloma.
虽不是好消息 至少有的治
It's not good news,but there are some treatments.
得抽点血
We have to drawsome blood.
我的呼吸呢?
What about my breathing?
并发的高粘稠度综合症破坏了肺部的血管
Associated hyperviscositysyndrome gummed up the blood vesselsin your lungs.
Chase医生说我尿钙浓度正常
Dr.Chase said my calciumis normal.
我们喊他蠢蛋医生
Mm,we call him dr.Idiot.
尿里也没有单株球蛋白
There's no m proteinin my urine.
怪异的陈述
Odd presentation.
更怪的是Cameron医生也不相信
So odd that dr.Camerondoesn't-- doesn't believe it either.
再给我12个小时
Just give me 12 more hours.
我们说好的
We had a deal.
不再做检查了
No more tests.
很公平
Fair enough.
再给我6个小时
Gimme six more hours.
没有证据你已病入膏肓
Listen,there is no evidencethat you are terminal.
你信守诺言么?
You a man of your wordor not?
不 事实上我并不
No,as a matter of fact,I'm not.
好
Fine.
让我出院
Then discharge me.
我的肺会慢慢充溢液体
My lungs will slowly fillwith fluid.
尽力呼吸 气喘不已
I'll gasp to catchevery breath.
却不能够
But never can.
每次呼吸都困难重重
Every breath will be petrifying.
漫长且饱受折磨
It'll be slow,painful,torturous.
你真想看我这么死
You're really gonna let medie like that?
你去哪里?
Where you going?
不去哪儿!
Nowhere!
能走的都出去
Everybody who can walkshould get outta here.
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
不能做什么?
Can't do what?
给一个疼痛中的病人施处方止疼剂
Administera prescription painkiller to a patientwho's in pain?
去 得保证有人在楼下餐厅看见你们
Go,make suresomebody sees you downstairs in the cafeteria.
不能让你这么做
I can't let you do this.
我要么痛死 要么直接死
Either I die in pain,or I just die.
这是争论焦点
That's what the argumentis here.
不 关系到你是自然死亡 还是被谋杀
No,it's about whether you die,or we murder you.
这里会发生的 只是有人被打上一针吗啡
What's gonna happen hereis that someone's getting a buttload of morphine.
我不能确保是谁被打针
I'm not sure exactly whoat this point.
我不想参与
I can't be a partof this.
谢谢
Thank you.
我总是好奇 另一端是怎样
I always wondered exactly what was on the other side.
什么也没有
Nothing.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
做喉镜
Getting a laryngoscope.
别傻站着 帮忙
Don't just stand there,help.
- 但你告诉他 - 是
But you told him-- yeah.
我称其为谎言
It was somethingI like to call a lie.
很糟 但比谋杀要好得多
Bad,I know,but it'sway further down the list than murder.
无意识 再不反抗
Unconscious,no more whining.
继续作检查
Keep testing him.
去拿个呼吸机
Go get a ventilatoR.
我不能整夜这样
I can't do this all night.
明智的人会同意
we can legally assume that he'd consent to whatever a reasonable person would consent to.
有理智的人都会反对被置于昏迷,仅仅满足你的好奇心
And a reasonable personwould obviously consent to being put in a comaagainst their will just to satisfyyour curiosity.
我要杀他 你气疯
I try to kill him,you're mad.
我不杀他 你又气疯
I don't kill him,you're mad.
他要的是尊严
All he wantedwas some dignity.
你没看到他么?
Were you in that roomwith him?
难道他被自己的积液窒息时,还能衣冠楚楚
Was he wearing a tux while hewas choking on his own plasma?
继续检查
Keep doing the tests.
抓紧时间 别出错
Take your time,do it right.
去
Go.
开工
Get to work.
等等!
Wait!
Cameron 你做他头部核磁成像时,切口为什么这么低
Cameron,why'd you do these cutsso far down on this mri of his head?
我想看到他的脑干和颈椎,保证他的膈肌没有瘫痪
I wanted to get his brain stemand his c-spine,make sure his diaphragmwasn't paralyzed.
你还拍到了他的肺
You also caught the topof his lungs.
有疤痕
There's scarring.
你知道无法以眼杀人么?
You do know that you can'treally pierce me with your stares?
肺部疤痕 加上不健康的骨髓,指向自身免疫性病
Lung scarring,along with the bad bone marrow,points to an autoimmune disease.
可能是肺纤维化
Could be pulmonary fibrosis.
或是狼疮
Or lupus.
我们治好他后 他可以自杀
He can kill himselfafter we get him better.
注射静脉免疫球蛋白 再做个直肠镜
Start him on an ivigfor the lupus,and get a colonoscopy.
狼疮可能藏在那里
Lupus could be hiding there.
我不能这么做
I can't do this.
戏剧女王
Drama queen.
降结肠无异常
Descending colon's clean.
移到乙状结肠
moving into the sigmoid.
还需要帮手
Sure could usea little more help around here.
她依照信仰行事
She's doingwhat she believes in.
如果她有原则的话 应该阻止我们
Yeah,if she was actingon principle,she'd be in here tryingto stop us.
她只是逃离了原则 逃避直面时的不安
All she's doing is running awayfrom the principle so she won't have to feeluncomfortable facing it.
你要是有原则 在认为House想杀他时,就该报警
And if you were actingon principle,you would've called the copswhen you thought house was killing the guy.
你最好快点
You better hurry up.
为什么?
Why?
我想她不会犹疑该怎么向Cuddy报告
I don't think she's gonnahave a problem deciding whatto tell cuddy.
氧饱和度89 还在降
O2 sats 89 and dropping.
我以为你在妊娠的前三个月,每星期只增重一磅
I thought you were only supposedto put on a pound a week during your last trimester.
我没有怀孕
I'm not pregnant.
我听说了你对Powell医生耍的花招
I heard about your little stuntwith dr.Powell.
不算花招
Mmm,not reallya stunt.
只是个把戏 诡计 障眼法
More of a trick,a ruse,a hoodwink.
谎言
A lie.
好吧
Okay.
说话也有好的
Lying is sometimes good,right?
比如 你想教人幽默
Like when you're tryingto teach someone a lesson about humility or something.
或是像我 救人一命
All I'm trying to dois save his life.
他可学不到什么
He's not gonnalearn anything.
我想原理是适用的
I just thought the sameprinciple might apply.
是
It does.
我本可以让他死去
I could've justlet him die.
让他活着可不会被起诉
Not gonna get suedfor keeping him alive.
也有可能
Well,we could.
我们完全违反了他的意志
We completely disregardedhis wishes.
你要我反对你?
Do you want meto disagree with you?
对你嚷嚷?
Want me to yell at you?
那样或许舒服点
It is comforting.
我们是医生
We're doctors.
治疗患者 不杀他们
We treat patients,we don't kill them.
你说的真对 Cuddy医生!
How right you are,dr.Cuddy!
我们也不给自己开处方,不从配药处偷样品
We also don't pad our bills,swipe samples from the pharmacy,
也不对病人的女儿浮想联翩
or fantasizeabout the teenage daughters of our patients either.
没错 最好是这样 你这头猪
True,better be true,and you're a pig.
你腿这样 我很难过
I'm sorryabout your leg.
我们确实该花点时间谈谈这个
Yeah,we really should spendsome time talking about that.
静脉免疫球蛋白让他情况更糟
The ivig made him worse.
氧饱和度直降
O2 sats plummeted.
可以肯定不是狼疮
So we knowit's not lupus.
还会是什么?
What else could it be?
先天性肺纤维化
Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.
得做个开胸肺活检来确定
Gonna need an open lungbiopsy to confirm.
要对他动手术?
So now we're gonnaoperate on the guy?
除非你发明了做开胸肺活检的新方法
Unless you've inventeda new way of doing an open lung biopsy.
搜查Powell医生的办公室时,有没有发现1967年1月马萨诸塞州医刊
When you searcheddr.Powell's office,did you find a copyof the january 1967 massachusetts medical journal?
什么?
Why?
我想 你不工作的话 也得打发时间
I just figured,if you'renot doing any work,you might like something to pass the time.
杂志插画能消磨时间
Centerfold's a killer.
你腿怎么样了?
How's your leg?
疼
It hurts.
会继续疼
It's gonna keep on hurting.
你会一直问?
You're gonna keep on asking?
Ezra Powell怎么样了?
How's ezra powell?
安稳地休息
Resting comfortably.
Cameron可不是这么说的
Hmm,that'snot what cameron says.
我讨厌在高中行医
I hate practicing medicinein high school.
他不是求你帮忙杀了他
He's not asking youto help him kill himself.
他只是求助
He's just asking for help.
疾病会杀死了他
The disease will kill him.
我明白他要什么
I know whathe was asking for.
我说了不
I just said no.
你以前做过
You've done it before.
很多次
Plenty of times.
只对没得救的病人
To patients that I knewwere terminal.
算了吧你
Oh,give me a break.
这和拯救生命一点也不搭界
This has nothing to dowith saving a life.
你只是不能接受在病人死前,没弄明白病因
You just can't bear the thoughtof a patient dying before you've been ableto figure out why.
如果为了浇灭我的自负,就一直拒绝治疗病人
If we're gonna keep refusingto cure patients just to rein in my ego,
那想吸收新病人 就有点困难了
then we might start to have a little problemwith patient recruitment.
担心你一周一个门诊病人的限额?
Worried about meetingyour one patient a week quota?
我是个跛子 你没忘吧?
I'm a cripple,remember?
总得给我行些方便
Accommodations must be made.
左肺叶锲状部被分离切除
Wedge of left lobe isolatedand removed.
夹紧
Clamp.
你为什么让我去查那篇文章?
Why'd you have melook up that article?
你没发现它很有意思吗?
Didn't you find itinteresting?
他给新生婴儿注射放射性制剂,只为看是否有尿道逆流
He injected newborn babieswith radioactive agents just to see if they hadurethral reflux.
他求知欲很强
He was curious.
他甚至没有告诉孩子的父母,他正在做的试验
He didn't eventell their parents he was doing an experiment.
他的同辈也是这么干的
He wasn't doing anythinghis peers weren't doing.
塔斯基大学梅毒实验,和威路布鲁克肺炎菌实验中的同辈?
His peersat tuskegee and willowbrook?
他无视了少数人的权利来拯救更多人
He ignored the rightsof a few to save many.
你不反对他所做的?
Soou're okaywith what he did.
我怎么想没用
Doesn't matterwhat I think.
你怎么想才重要
It's what you thinkthat's relevant.
你以为我看低他 就会帮你是不是?
Because if I think less of him,I'll help you more?
你错了
You're wrong.
即使一个病人在外面做了坏事
The fact that a patientdid bad things doesn't change anything.
对自己的身体仍然有支配的权利
He still deserves to havesome control over his own body.
如果由他支配自己的身体 他就会死
If he had controlof his own body,he'd be dead.
我说的是某种程度的支配
Some control.
可以保守治疗 不害死他
We can withhold treatmentwithout killing him.
不 不行!
No,you can't!
要么帮他生 要么帮他死
You either help him live,or you help him die.
难以两全
You can't ha it both ways.
我猜不是特发性肺纤维化
I guess it's not ipf.
也许他马上死掉 会让大家轻松点
Or maybe he'll die right now,and make everything easyfor all of us.
心率过快
Heart rate's fast.
血压过低
bp's low.
右边听不到呼吸声
No breath soundson the right side.
他右肺失去功能了
He's dropped his right lung.
空气堵塞胸腔 挤压心脏
Air's building up in his chest,and pressing his heart.
心率正在下降
Heart rate's decreasing.
血压稳定
Bp's stabilizing.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
左半边对疼痛刺激有退缩反应,但右半边没有
Withdraws from pain stimulion the left side,but not the right.
那些只是由反射弧起作用
Those are just reflex arcs.
他现在在麻醉状态下
He's under anesthesia.
可能他某处失去知觉了
Or he's lost sensationin some places.
或者是缺氧导致他中枢神经麻痹
Or the hypoxia from the arreststunned his cns.
只有一种可能
Only one way to tell.
做体感诱发电位
Do somatosensory evokedpotentials.
他在昏迷中 不能做那个
We can't do thatwhile he's in a coma.
只有两个办法
Only two ways to tell.
找把锤子来测试他的深层肌腱反射
Get a hammer and checkhis deep tendon reflexes.
不会有用
Won't work.
他需要肌肉松弛剂 才可以使用呼吸机
He needs muscle relaxantsto be on the ventilator.
那么只有一条办法了
Only one more wayto tell.
瞳孔反射
Pupillary reflexes.
那些测试都是由脑干决定的
All that testsis the brainstem.
瞧 还是我对的
See,I was right.
只有一个办法
Only one way to tell.
做体感诱发电位
Do somatosensory evokedpotentials.
当他处在昏迷中 做不了
I just said we can't do thatwhile he's in a coma.
那么把他叫醒
So wake him up.
不要朝有光的地方走
Don't go towards the light.
否则会摔断你的髋骨
U'll fall and breakyour hip.
发生什么了?
What's happening?
你打了个盹
You took a little nap.
我告诉过我不想--
I know I told youI didn't want--
对不起 我有只耳朵有点聋
sorry,a little deafin one ear.
你的骨髓细胞减少
Your bone marrowwas hypocellular.
排除了狼疮和肺部纤维化的可能性
Ruled out lupusand pulmonary fibrosis.
但是可能攻击到你的神经
But it looks like it could beattacking your nerves.
这么看来全白干了
So this is all a waste.
巨大的失败
Huge failure.
怎么可能
Impossible.
你是Gregory House
You're gregory house.
得在你皮肤上帖些传感器
We need to attach some sensorsto your skin.
不
No.
听着 我们不能按你想的去做
Look,we can't dowhat you want.
安排了一名护士盯着你,所以你自己也不行
We've assigned a nurse to watch you so you can't do iteither.
所以你最好老老实实做检测
So you might as welljust let us do the test.
不 我要出院
No,I want to bedischarged.
你不能出院
you can't be discharged.
你胸腔里还插了两根管子
You've gottwo chest tubes in.
那就把它们拿出来
Then take em out.
省省吧你
Oh,get over yourself.
呼吸机让你肺部鼓起
The ventilator puffed up your lungs.
再过几个小时 你就好了
You'll be finefor a few hours.
只要让我们做些检测
Just let us runthe tests.
好吧
Okay.
但是先把你清理干净一点
But first,let's clean you upa little.
什--什么?
Wha--whuh?
感觉不错吧?
Does that feel nice?
你想证明什么?
What are you tryingto prove?
只是把他清理干净
Just cleaning him up.
看起来像什么?
What does it look like?
别管藏在床单后面的人
Pay no attention to the manbehind the curtain.
出去!
Get out!
好 我这就走
Okay,I'm going already.
没看到我是个跛子吗?
Can't you seeI'm a cripple?
好了 你勾起我的好奇心了
okay,so you got me curious.
我是对的
I was right.
攻击他肺的正攻击他的神经
Whatever is attacking his lungsis attacking his nerves.
你是从朝他身上泼冰水得出来的吗?
You got that by splashingice water on him?
左腿 腹部 右臂没有知觉
No sensation in the left leg,abdomen,right arm.
太高估科技的力量了
Technology's overrated.
核磁共振扫描无异常说明,影响的是外周神经
That means the clean mriof his brain means it's just affectingthe peripheral nerves.
还有骨髓
And bone marrow.
川崎病可以解释肾衰竭
Kawasaki's would explainthe kidney failure.
或者是淋巴瘤
Or lymphoma.
还有结节病
Or sarcoidosis.
都是可以治疗的 问题是究竟是哪个
All potentially treatable.Question is which.
得在下一幕中把混蛋揪出来
We need to catchthe little bastards in the act.
人最大的器官是什么?
What's the largest organ?
皮肤
Skin.
需要一小块
We need to geta piece.
只需等他丢下皮肤 离开房间,悄悄潜进去 偷一小块出来
Sure,we'll just waituntil he leaves his room without his skin,sneak in,and take a piece.
你去取一块皮肤做活检
I want you to get a skin samplefor a biopsy.
我去Johnny Damon那儿做个脚底按摩
And I want to get a foot massagefrom johnny damon.
川崎病 淋巴瘤 结节病都是可以治疗的
Kawasaki's disease,lymphoma,and sarcoidosis are all treatable.
也有可能是另外一百种绝症
And it could be 100 other thingsthat aren't treatable.
这你不知道
You have no idea.
但你知道
But you do.
你什么都知道
You know everything.
- 我没说我,- 一点没错!
I didn't say that I-- exactly!
你无法判断是在帮他还是在害他
You can't decideif we're helping or hurting him.
他是好还是坏
If he's good or bad.
或者你想要纸袋 塑料袋 还是麻布口袋
Or if you want paper,plastic,or a burlap sack.
尽你该死的职吧
Do your damn job.
我不会骗他
I'm not gonna lie to him.
很好 去告诉他事实
Fine,tell the truth.
别忘了给我留一磅肉
Just get me a poundof flesh.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
House想要活检你的皮肤 让我来取样
House wants to biopsyyour skin.He sent me to get it.
呵 你就同意了
Ah,and you agreed.
让你进入昏迷状态 以及随后的检测,都和我无关
I had nothing to dowith putting you in a coma,or any of the subsequent tests.
所以我们现在这样
Which brings us to now.
我读了你的论文
I read some of your articles.
有很多
There were a lot of them.
1967年 马萨诸塞州医学期刊
1967 massachusetts medical journal.
你给婴儿给放射性药 诸如此类
You radiated babies,just like that.
没有表格 没有询问 什么都没有
No forms,no questions,nothing.
谁能知道你引发了多少癌症?
Who knows how many cancersyou caused?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的确知道发明了一项技术,防止了其他千万孩子得致命的肾衰竭
What I do know is we discoveredtechniques that prevent fatal kidney failuresin hundreds of thousands of other kids.
你一点不悔恨
You're not sorry.
我对做过的从不后悔
I don't regret what I did.
病人的知情同意权阻碍了研究的发展
Informed consent,patient rights holds back research.
你他妈在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
知情同意权也阻碍了我们的诊断
Informed consentis holding back our diagnosis.
做得好
Good for you.
你终于有支持的观点了
Finally standing upfor something.
追随你的信念吧
Acting on what you believe.
House医生?
Dr.House?
嗨
Hi.
你好吗?
How are you?
不如你想象的那么好
Not as goodas you think I am.
别怕 我不是在跟踪你
Don't worry,I'm not stalking you.
我老爸把他的药给丢了
My dad just losthis medicine.
只好再回来开份处方
He had to come backfor another prescription.
哦 是啊
Yeah,right.
他正在大街上朝这里走 是不是?
He's moving it on the street,isn't he?
是的 我老爸 梅斯·金皮(毒品贩子)
Yeah,my dad,the meth kingpin.
你怎么一个电话都不回我?
Why haven't you returnedany of my calls?
我打算回的
I plan to.
在若干年后
In a couple of years.
我打电话只想说谢谢,还想告诉你 给我印象多深刻
I was just callingto say thank you,and to tell youhow impressed I was.
你只是看看 就诊断出我老爸的病
You diagnosed my dadby just looking at him.
我还碰过他的腺体
Felt his glands too.
噢 老爸来了 我得走了
Oh,there's my dad.I gotta go.
嗯 我也是
Yeah,me too.
对了 你不必再等上几年才回我的电话
Oh,and you really don'thave to wait a couple yearsto return my calls.
只需6个月
Just six months.
我就18岁了
Till i turn 18.
也不是川崎病
It's not kawasaki's either.
下一个是什么?
What's next?
刚果红
Congo red.
淀粉样变性病?
Amyloidosis?
我说刚果红 还会有别的意思吗?
What the hell else would I meanby congo red?
不在列表上
It's not on the list.
不可能在列表上
There's no reasonfor it to be on the list.
变态蛋白在他身体的细胞内增长
An abnormal proteinis building up inside the cellsof his body,
关闭器官功能 一个接一个
shutting down his organs,one by one.
能解释所有 X射线下的渗透,骨髓 肾衰竭
Explains everything,the infiltrates on the x-ray,the bone marrow,kidney failure.
排除淀粉样变性病 因为和第一症状不符
We rejected amyloidosisbecause it didn't fit the first symptom we found.
应该会影响心脏
It would affect his heart.
影响了
It did.
在压力测试中没反应出来
It wasn'ton the stress test.
没有逼得更紧
We didn't push himhard enough.
加入染色剂 看个清楚
Add the stain,let's find out.
加入刚果红
Congo red added.
改变光偏振
Change the polarizationof the light already.
这是可以治疗的
That meansit should be treatable.
你怎么想出来的
How the hell did you pullthat out of your--
不是我 我的缪斯女神
not out of mine,I had a muse.
哦 天
Oh,god.
淀粉样A蛋白
Protein type aa.
- House医生,- 你得的是淀粉样变性病
Dr.House-- you have amyloidosis.
在你的肺 肾 骨髓 和脑中
It's in your lungs,kidneys,bone marrow,and brain.
我现在能信你吗?
Why should I believe you now?
要是说谎 不会告诉你子类型是AA蛋白
If I was lying,I wouldn'ttell you the subtype is aa.
到晚期了
It's terminal.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
终于得到答案
You got your answer.
夜晚的弗雷斯诺
fresno,by night
六个月 倒计时
xxx and counting
Ezra Powell昨晚死了
ezra powell passed awaylast night.
我想你已经知道了吧
But I'm sure you already knew about that.
不
Nope.
我才进来
I just got in.
护士2点记录时 他还很稳定
The nurse charted at 2:00 amhe was stable.
呼吸吃力 尚规则
Breathing labored,but regular.
但2:30 他突然停止了
Then at 2:30,he suddenly stopped.
你知道些什么?
You know anythingabout that?
我若知道 你想知道吗?
If I did,would you reallywant to know?
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.